OKIKIAYO NDUBUISI GIDI-FANIMOKUN

21 Reginald Street, LU2 7QZ, Luton, United Kingdom +447943240374 mastergidi556@gmail.com Website | LinkedIn | GitHub

Profile

Enthusiastic full stack developer with 3 years of experience building and maintaining responsive web applications in the Fintech industry. Proficient in React, Typescript, JavaScript, HTML and CSS; plus backend technologies that include C# ASP.Net Core, SQL and RESTAPI. I look forward to bringing this experience with me to my next role.

Professional Experience

Frontend Web Developer (Remote) - Passfolio, San Francisco, USA, March 2019 - May 2022

- Implemented multiple dynamic and browser compatible pages using React, JavaScript, HTML5, & CSS.
- Automation testing with Jest to identify bugs and technical issues during development and deployment.
- Collaborated with the UI/UX team to improve existing applications for better user experience.
- Performed requirements analysis, design, development and test management.
- Participating in peer code reviews to maintain code and design consistency across different team members.
- Executing exemplary version control using Git, ensuring accurate record keeping.
- Monitoring website performance and rectifying front-end-related issues.

IT Service Desk Technician - Galaxy Backbone Plc, January 2017 - December 2017

- Provided 1st line support for colleagues and site visitors in the use of a range of business critical software solutions.
- Recorded support requests in the central ticketing system (Jira) and track and manage assigned (Jira) tickets, whilst also escalating to IT Helpdesk Technicians
- Provided support for users in the operation of a range of hardware including printers, scanners and other external peripherals'.
- Ensured that resources within the IT suites are supported through the development of printed and online instructional material to reduce call rates and enable users to become more self-sufficient.
- Delivered inductions and basic training in the use of facilities and services provided by the IT department.
- Managed IT equipment that is issued or loaned to colleagues.

Key Skills

- React
- JavaScript
- Typescript
- REST API
- HTML 5
- CSS

- Object oriented programming with C#
- ASP.NET core (MVC)
- Entity Framework
- Node
- Office 365

- AWS
- Postgres

Education & Qualifications

September 2021 - October 2022 MSc Project Management, University of Bedfordshire, United -

Kingdom

January 2018 – January 2019 MSc Software Development, Coventry University, United -Kingdom

September 2012 – June 2016 BSc (Hons) Computer Science, Afe-Babalola University, Nigeria.

Certifications

Chartered Management Institute Level 7 award in Professional Consulting, 9th October 2018.

Chartered Management Institute Level 7 Award in Strategic Management and Leadership, 9th October 2018.

Publications

Online Support System for Diabetes management (International Journal of Computer Applications)
https://www.ijcaonline.org/archives/volume152/number10/26353-2016911454